Like I say, welcome brothers and sisters
to another Wednesday question and
answer. We open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep. Brother
Sean, and God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any grave in
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children, unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Six days shall thou labor
and do all thy work. But the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in the midst, and rested the seventh
day. Wherefore the Lord blessed the
Sabbath day, and hollowed it. Honor thy
father and thy mother, that thy days may
be long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not coveret thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ax, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. We
read Exodus the 20th chapter verses 1-1
17. May the Lord have a blessing to the
reading and teaching of his word. In
Jesus name we pray. Amen. Amen. Amen.
Amen. So here on question and answer,
you can ask us a question and we'll
answer it according to the King James
Bible. And if we cannot find the answer,
we will seek further counsel to bring
you an answer at a later time. The
questions we will not answer are the
vague and the long scripture questions
as well as questions of debate. We are
not here to debate. We are here to
spread the true gospel of Jesus. So,
please be as direct as possible with
your questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also, keep in mind that this is
a live stream, so feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just ask that you
keep your questions to a two scripture
maximum. But let me introduce you the
family on the panel this evening.
Brother Dre, good evening. Brother
Julius, good evening everybody. Good
evening everybody. Brother Jerome, rest
in peace.
Brother Sean, good evening.
Sister Deborah, good evening.
And we have the guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's
Q&A. Hannah Israel says, "I see people
at the class putting their food in their
car on the dashboard to heat their food.
Is that considered the same as heating
your food with an appliance?"
No, that's not the same. totally
different. If you want to put your food
on the dash of your car and let the sun
provide a little heat for you, that is
all right because an appliance is a
piece of equipment that's used for
either heating, cooling, or warming. So,
the
dashboard and the sun. Hey, that is a
help meat for those that's trying to
keep the Sabbath day and want their
sandwiches to either be warm or a good
room temperature. So, hey, it's okay if
you want to put your sandwich or your
food on the dash and let the sun
naturally bring about some heat for it.
That is okay. And um that's all we got
on
that. And we hope that that answers your
question as we continue to move on to
our next question. Moving on. Mark Ash
says, "Can I offer a sacrifice of thanks
on an altar on my property as they did
before the Levitical
priesthood? Or would it or would that
violate any laws, statutes, or
commandments?"
All right, brother Julius. What about
this sacrifice on an altar that they
have on their own property? Well, first
of all, we're no longer uh Good evening
everybody. We're no longer under the
Levitical priesthood. So, we don't have
altars on our property. The uh the
second thing is uh we are under the
Melchisedc or the Jesus priesthood. And
let's show you what they did in the
ancient days. Let's go to Acts the 17th
chapter.
Acts chapter 17,
Sean, and we're going to read verses 23
and 24. This is when Paul was on Mars
Hill and he saw the Athenians and stuff,
some of the practices that they were
doing. Pick it up at verse 23.
For as I passed by and beheld your
devotions, I found an altar with the
inscription to the unknown God, whom
therefore ye ignorantly worship. Him
declare unto you.
Him declare I to you. Go ahead in verse
24. Look what Look what the Lord uh had
Paul tell the Athenians. Go ahead. God
that made the world and all things
therein, seeing that he is Lord of
heaven and earth, dwelleth not in
temples made with hands. He don't dwell
in temples made in hands. Go ahead.
Neither is worship with men's hands, as
though he needed anything, seeing he
giveth to all life and breath and all
things. So, how do we worship God? How
do we supposed to worship God? Let's go
to Hebrews the 13th chapter and we going
to pick it up at verse
15. Hebrews the 13th chapter. God John 4
and 24. God is a spirit and they that
worship him must worship him in spirit
and in
truth. Hebrews 13 we going 15 to 17. Go
ahead Sean. By him therefore let us
offer the sacrifice of praise to God
continually. that is the fruit of our
lips giving thanks to his name. So what
you do you say thank you Jesus for
blessing me for for all things. Go
ahead. But to do good and to communicate
forget not for with such sacrifices God
is well pleased. For with such
sacrifices, God is well pleased with you
giving him praises with the thanks
coming from your lips, from your voice,
you know, through prayer, through
meditation, through fasting. He's
pleased with that, not with any altars
because if you make an altar, sooner or
later you're going to worship it. That's
all I have.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we continue to move on to
our next question. Next question. Little
Mama Hayes says, "The new Pope Leo is
from the Augustine order lineage, which
has something to do with the
transatlantic slave trade. Is it true
that Rome had a part in the
transatlantic slave trade?"
All right, brother Julius, we know a lot
of people had something to do with the
slave trade. Can you shed some light?
But not the Roman, not
Rome. Although Ro in ancient Rome, they
had a system of slavery, but that came
through uh wars that they won. They
would uh beat the people down and they
would enslave the women, the uh the men
or whoever they conquered, you know. So
they had ancient Rome had slaves. That's
how they got their slave through
conquest. Uh uh or if you were uh born
uh to a family that was already in
slavery, then slavery that became the
Roman. But through uh the transatlantic
slave trade, which happened in the 1500s
and the 16 uh and it was abolished in
the 1800s, that was so far removed from
Rome. that had nothing to do with the
Roman Empire, sisters and brothers, you
know. And by the way, uh this Pope
Augustine, uh Pope Leo the 14th, he came
from the Augustine order, which mean
that he was just a frier, one of the f
uh friars um that devoted themselves to
chastity uh to the order of um what they
call the Austinian uh order, Augustine
of Hippo. So that's all it was. He was
just a man that was dedicated to prayer,
to fasting, and uh uh what you call when
um when a man is not allowed to
marry had nothing to do with
slavery or transatlantic slavery. That's
all I got on that.
All right. Thank you for that. We hope
that answered your question as we move
on to our next next one. Justin Ulissi
says, "Married twice, divorced twice. No
consummation took place both times. Can
I have a family?"
Married twice, divorced twice. No
consummation. Can I have a family? Guest
call up.
I'm going to leave that to the Lord
because if you got married twice, you
may eat fouls even though you didn't get
uh uh you didn't get sexually
involved. So, I can't answer that
question.
All right, we'll leave that question
right there and we're going to continue
our journey. Sister Deborah, yes. The
right way says, "I was talking to the
Baptist pastor and I brought up Hebrews
10 verse 26 and he disagreed with it and
asked, "Did people through the Bible sin
willfully like Adam and Eve and David,
etc."
All right. She was talking to a Baptist
pastor. He was against it. What you
saying, Brother Dre? Well, that Baptist
pastor was against the word of God, and
I don't know what he a pastor of if he's
against the word of God. But let's go
read Hebrews 10 and pick it up at verse
26. Go ahead, brother, when you get it.
For if we sin willfully after that we
have received the knowledge of the
truth, there remain of no more sacrifice
for sins. Go ahead. but a certain
fearful looking for of judgment and
fiery indignation which shall devour the
adversary.
Go ahead. He that despised Moses's law
died without mercy under two or three
witnesses.
Of how much sure punishment suppose ye
shall he be thought worthy? who have
tried and underfoot the Son of God, and
have counted the blood of the covenant,
wherewith he was sanctified an unholy
thing, and have done despite unto the
spirit of grace.
This person is co-signing, doing despite
the spirit of grace and counting the
blood of the covenant an unholy thing
and living life in a sinful way despite
the spirit of grace. This Baptist pastor
should not be something somebody you
should listen to. Let's go to Ezekiel
now. Ezekiel 18. Ezekiel
18. Maybe you could give this BA B B B B
B B B B B B B B B B B B B B B B B B B B
B B B B B B B B B B B B B B B Baptist
pastor this and stamp on it. Thus said
the Lord. This is the word of the Lord
here. Ezekiel 18 and and read verse one
and we going to skip to verse four. Go
ahead, brother. The word of the Lord
came unto me again, saying Uhhuh. ye
that ye use this proverb concerning the
land of Israel, saying, "The fathers
have eaten sour grapes, and the
children's teeth are set on edge." So,
in other words, the children ain't going
to pay for the father's sins. Skip down
to verse four. Go ahead. Behold, all
souls are mine. As the soul of the
father, so also the soul of the son is
mine. The soul that sinnth, it shall
die. Now, we going to either believe
this Baptist pastor or we going to
believe the word of God. It says,
"Behold, all souls are mine as the soul
of the father also the soul of the son,
the soul that sinnth, it shall die."
Skip down to verse 26, brother, and go
ahead.
When the righteous man turneth away from
his righteousness, and committh
iniquity, and dieth in them, for his
iniquity that he hath done, shall he
die. We talking about him dying in his
iniquity. And our time is always, you
don't know your time. The book tell you,
a righteous man falls seven times, but
get back up. What if he don't have time
to get back up? You don't want to roll
the dice like that.
So this pastor that's saying what he's
saying is wrong. Go ahead, brother. Read
a little more.
27 again. When the wicked man turneth
away from his wickedness that he hath
committed, and do of that which is
lawful and right, he shall save his soul
alive.
Go ahead. because he considerth and
turneth away from all his transgressions
that he hath committed, he shall surely
live. He shall not die. Read verse 30,
brother, and that'll be it. Therefore, I
will judge you, oh house of Israel,
everyone according to his ways, said the
Lord God. Repent and turn yourselves
from all your transgressions, so
iniquity shall not be your ruin. Cuz it
will be your ruin. Read the next two
verses, brother. Just end it with that.
Go ahead. Cast away from you all your
transgressions, whereby ye have
transgressed, and make you a new heart
and a new spirit. For why will ye die,
oh house of Israel? Go ahead. Have no
pleasure in the death of him that dieth,
said the Lord God. Wherefore turn
yourselves and live ye.
Notice it said the Lord
God. Now this Baptist pastor don't have
nowhere that he can put you in. But if
if anybody listens to him, he mess
around and get them cut off. Do not
listen to him. That's all I got.
Yeah. Hey, brother Drake, can we read
just one verse in that Jeremiah 12 and
10? Absolutely, brother. All right,
let's go to Jeremiah 12 and 10 and read
that one verse for me there,
brother. Jeremiah 12 and 10.
Many pastors have destroyed my vineyard.
They have trotted my portion underfoot.
They have made my pleasant portion a
desolate wilderness. So no matter what
denomination, Andre Lord say many
pastors, they come from all
denominations trying to destroy God's
people in his word. That is right,
brother. Yeah.
Yeah. So thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question as we
continue to move on to our next next
question. Valencia would like an
explanation in Hebrews
9 16 and 17. Who are the testators?
Who are the testators in that Hebrew
9 16 and 17? Brother Jerome,
let's go read
it. Hebrews 9 verse 16 and 17. You get
it? Go ahead.
For where a testament is, there must
also of necessity be the death of the
testator. For a testament is a force
after men are dead. Otherwise, it is of
no strength at all while the testator
live.
Um the test stator um in this chapter is
talking about
uh mediator of a covenant in this case
and Moses uh he was the mediator of the
old testament but in this case it's
talking about the old covenant okay cuz
testament in this chapter is really
referring to covenants and as far as the
new covenant Jesus will be considered to
testator of the new testament slash new
covenant. So he the mediator of the new
covenant. So that's what the testate is.
He's the mediator of the covenants.
Okay. So let's go. Can can you read
that? Uh 18-
21 18. Whereupon neither the first
testament was dedicated without blood.
For when Moses had spoken every precept
to all the people according to the law,
he took the blood of calves and of goats
with water and scarlet wool and hissop
and sprinkle both the book and all the
people.
Saying this is the blood of the
testament which God have enjoined unto
you. Meaning the blood of the covenant
is really what that word testament mean
there. Go ahead. Moreover, he sprinkled
with blood both the tabernacle and all
the vessels of the ministry. And almost
all things are by the law purged with
blood. And without shedding of Go ahead.
Go ahead. And without shedding of blood
is no remission. Yeah. And so Jesus
being the test of the new covenant, his
blood was shed. And when Moses was
mediating under the old covenant, he
used the blood of animals. All
right. All right. So now,
uh, let's go to the 12th chapter because
I just want to establish. We ain't going
to read all these verses. I had some
other verses, but it's not necessary.
Uh, go to the 12th chapter and read
verse 24 cuz I just want to establish
when he said New Testament, he really
talking about new covenant. And Jesus is
the mediator of the new covenant. Okay.
So let's read verse chapter 12 verse 24.
Hebrews 12 and 24. It reads, "And to
Jesus the mediator of the new covenant
and to the blood of sprinkling that
speaketh better things than that of
Abel." Yeah, cuz I was going to tie that
with the 15th verse. And I just read it
right quick in that ninth chapter. It
said, "And for this cause he is the
mediator of the New Testament." It mean
new covenant and that's why I took you
to that 12th chapter to establish that.
That's all I got on.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question as we
move on to our next. Moving on. Stephen
Gooas asked in Zechariah 14 16 and 17.
Is this Jesus kingdom or the father's
kingdom?
Zechariah 14:16 and 17. Is this Jesus
kingdom or is this the father's kingdom,
brother Jerome? Uh, it's Jesus kingdom.
But let's go read the verses that you
gave. Zechariah 14 verse 16 and
17. You get it? Go ahead.
And it shall come to pass that everyone
that is left of all the nations which
came against Jerusalem shall even go up
from year to year to worship the king,
the Lord of hosts, and to keep the feast
of tabernacles.
And it shall be that whosoever will not
come up of all the families of the earth
unto Jerusalem to worship the king, the
Lord of hosts, even upon them shall be
no rain. Yeah. So this is definitely
this is definitely Jesus' kingdom and
and we know that Jesus kingdom he going
to have flesh and blood flesh and blood
men going to be in Jesus' kingdom. It's
going to be spirit beings in Jesus
kingdom too. But the point I want to
make is Jesus's kingdom going to have
flesh and blood men. But the father's
kingdom not going to have no flesh and
blood men in his kingdom. Okay. So, I'm
going to read some verses that that's uh
associated with Jesus' kingdom. Let you
know you got flesh and blood in there
going on uh in that kingdom. Okay. So,
let's go to
um Isaiah
66. Matter of fact, yeah, Isaiah 66.
Pick it up at the 15 and read it to the
17.
Go ahead when you get it. For behold,
the Lord will come with fire and with
his chariots like a whirlwind. Surrender
his anger with fury and his rebuke with
flames of fire. It's the coming of the
Lord. Come on. For by fire and by his
sword will the Lord plead with all
flesh. He ain't going to kill all flesh.
He going to leave some flesh people. He
ain't going to kill every flesh and
blood person on this planet. Go ahead.
And the slain of the Lord shall be many.
They that sanctify themselves and purify
themselves in the gardens behind one
tree in the midst, eating swine's flesh,
and the abomination and the mouse shall
be consumed together, said the Lord.
Verse 19 and 20, and I will set a sign
among them, and I will send those that
escape of them unto the nations. Ones he
did kill, the ones he did kill, he left
them alive. They still flesh and blood.
Go ahead. to Tarses, to Pull, and to
Lug, that draw the boat, to Tubal, and
to Jan, to the aisles of far off, that
have not heard my fame, neither have
seen my glory, and they shall declare my
glory among the Gentiles. Them flesh and
blood Gentiles. Go ahead. And they shall
bring all your brethren for an offering
unto the Lord out of all nations upon
horses and in chariots and in litters
and upon mules and upon swift beasts to
my holy mountain Jerusalem, says the
Lord. Go ahead. As the children of
Israel bring an offering in a clean
vessel into the house of the Lord. Get
down to verse 23. And it shall come to
pass that from one new moon to another,
and from one Sabbath to another, shall
all flesh come to worship before me,
said the Lord. All flesh that's left
alive, they going to come and and make
that
pilgrimage to the Lord where he going to
be at. And that's Jerusalem when he
return. Okay? That's flesh and blood
people right there. All right? One more
place and I'll be done. Isaiah the 2
chapter verse two uh verse two read to
the four and that'll be
it. You get it? Go ahead and read. And
it shall come to pass in the last days
that the mountain of the Lord's house
shall be established in the top of the
mountains and shall be exalted above the
hills and all nations shall flow into
it. That's right. All them flesh and
blood people among the nations that's
left, they going to make that
pilgrimage. Come on. And many people
shall go and say, "Come ye, and let us
go up to the mountain of the Lord, to
the house of the God of Jacob, and he
will teach us of his ways, and we will
walk in his paths. For out of Zion shall
go forth the law, and the word of the
Lord from Jerusalem." Uh-huh. And he
shall judge among the nations, and shall
rebuke many people, and they shall beat
their swords into plowshares, and their
spears into pruning hooks. Nation shall
not lift up sword against nation,
neither shall they learn war anymore.
Yeah, that's that's all I got.
All right, brother. Thank you for that.
As we continue to move on to our next
question. Next question. Little Mama
Haynes says, "I
have never spoken in tongues yet. My
family member says, "I'm not yet filled
with the Holy Spirit, so I cannot
understand the Bible word of God." Is
there a scripture I can lead them
to? All right. Say they have never
spoken in tongues and their family
members say that they aren't filled with
the Holy Spirit. So, it looks like the
family member needs a little light, too.
Brother Dre, what you say? Yeah. Um, if
you speaking in English, you speaking in
a tongue. That's a language. But let's
go to uh John 14 right quick. And we
gonna look at something there real quick
because she said you you uh you don't
have the Holy Spirit, so you can't
understand the word of God. But I don't
know nobody that's speaking in tongues
that's interpreting what they're saying
that they understand what they saying.
So that's out of order. But 14 and 15.
Go ahead, brother.
John 14 verse 15. Go ahead. If ye love
me, keep my commandments. Uhhuh. Go
ahead. And I will pray the father and he
shall give you another comforter that he
may abide with you forever. Yes, sir. Go
ahead. Even the Spirit of truth, whom
the world cannot receive, because it
seeth him not, neither know of him, but
ye know him, for he dwelleth with you
and shall be in you. Now, what is this
comforter, and what is this spirit of
truth? Skip down to verse 26. Go ahead.
But the comforter, which is the Holy
Ghost, whom the Father will send in my
name, he shall teach you all things and
bring all things to your remembrance,
whatsoever I have said unto you. Notice
he didn't say, "He shall have you speak
in tongues." He said, "He shall teach
you all things. the Holy Ghost, the
comforter whom the Father will send in
my name. He shall teach you all things
and bring all things to your
remembrance. Didn't say anything about
speaking in different languages. Now,
let's go to First Corinthians 14 right
quick. 1 Corinthians
14 and pick it up at verse one. And we
going to
skip. Go ahead.
Follow after charity and desire
spiritual gifts, but rather that ye may
prophesy.
Rather, that ye may prophesy. Follow
spiritual gifts, but I'd rather that ye
may prophesy. Go ahead. For he that
speaketh in an unknown tongue speaketh
not unto men, but unto God. For no man
for no man understand of him, how be it
in the spirit he speaketh mysteries. Now
if you speak in a mystery and no man
understand you, you not edifying nobody.
What's up? That's right. And read verse
four, brother. Go ahead. He that
speaketh in an unknown tongue edify
himself, but he that prophesieth edifith
the church. So if you speak in the word
of God, you edifying the church. Go
ahead. I would that ye all spake with
tongues, but rather that ye
prophesy. For greater is he that
prophesieth than he that speaketh with
tongues, except he interpret that the
church may receive edify. Notice it
says, "Greater is he that prophesy than
he that speaketh with
tongues." Greater. So you speaking the
word of God. Now skip down to verse 10.
Verse 10. Go ahead, brother.
There are it may be so many kinds of
voices in the world, and none of them is
without signification. Go ahead.
Therefore, if I know not the meaning of
the voice, I shall be unto him that
speaketh a barbarian, and he that
speaketh shall be a barbarian unto me.
So, if I'm speaking in a tongue and I
don't know what you
saying, both is barbarians. I don't know
what you saying and you don't know what
I'm saying. Both is barbarians. That's
verse 11. Yes, it is. Okay. Skip down to
verse 24, brother. Go ahead. But if all
prophesy, and there come in one that
believeth not, or one unlearned, he is
convinced of all, he is judged of all.
So he is convinced of all if this man is
speaking the word of God. Now what
happened in Acts the 2 chapter is they
all came together and when you read Acts
it tells you that was Jews from
everywhere and they heard the word of
God spoken in the language wherein they
were born. It wasn't some unknown
language. It was in the language wherein
they were born. Skip down to verse 27.
Brother,
if any man speak in an unknown tongue,
let it be by two, or at the most by
three, and that by course and let one
interpret. Go ahead. But if there be no
interpreter, let him keep silence in the
church, and let him speak. Go ahead. And
let him speak to himself and to God. Let
him keep silence if there's no
interpreter. So if nobody knows what you
saying, let him keep silence. But let me
show you one other thing about when the
Holy Ghost fell, what happened here? Did
they speak in tongues or what did they
do? Let's go to Acts 4. Acts 4 and we
just going to read one verse here. Acts
4 and we going to read verse 31. Acts 4
and
31. When you get it, go ahead, brother.
And when they had prayed, the place was
shaken where they were assembled
together, and they were all filled with
the Holy Ghost, and they spake the word
of God with
boldness. Notice they spake the word of
God with
boldness. They spoke the word of God.
They didn't
speak whatever it is that they be
speaking.
So, we just read, "Greater is he that
prophesyth than he that speaketh with an
unknown tongue." Paul even said, "I
rather speak five words than 10,000 in
an unknown tongue." Yes, sir. I hope
that helps. Yeah. Why don't you read
that? Tongues are for
That's right. Tongues is fine,
believers. Let's read that.
That's uh 1 Corinthians 14 and uh that's
14 and 23. Go ahead.
If therefore the whole church be come
together into one place and all speak
with tongues and there come in those
that are unlearned or unbelievers. Will
they not say they that ye are
mad? But read that 22. I think that's
what he 22. Go ahead. 22.
Tongues are for a sign, not to them that
believe, but to them that believe not.
But prophesying serveth not for them
that believe not, but for them which
believe. Thank you, guest caller. That
is correct. Tongues are for a sign.
Not Go ahead, guest caller. And Jesus
when they asked
him when the apostles came to him and
asked for a sign he gave a sign of
Jonah. But he said an evil in adulterous
generation seeketh after signs. Mhm.
So if you speak out to sign and try to
say that somebody uh uh don't have the
Holy Spirit because uh uh they don't
speak in tongues, then uh uh you you
Jesus call you an evil and adulterous
generation. You seek out the sign as far
as you feeling with being filled with
the Holy Ghost. Jesus told you in s and
and in and St. John 6 and 63 the words
that he speak they are spirit
that is life. So now if you know the
word you full of the word of God you
understand word of God you're the one
that's full of the spirit the one that
told you speak in tongues they are
deficient and don't have the spirit of
God in them. That's all I have to say.
That is correct. Thank you guys call.
All right. We hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question. Next question. Bronnie asks,
"What does God say about a narcissistic
husband? How do you deal with them? Can
you leave a narcissistic husband?"
We got a few of them in the creation.
Guess caller.
Well, I read one thing and I leave it
there. Let's go into first Corinthians
7. Yep. And we going to read verses 10
and 11 when she said, "Can I leave a
narcissist?"
Let's see what the Lord said about
leaving. Go ahead.
And unto the Mary I command, yet not I,
but the Lord. Let not the wife depart
from her husband.
But and if she depart, let her remain
unmarried or be reconciled to her
husband. And let not the husband put
away his wife.
That's all I have to say.
All right. For those that may wonder
about that word, narcissistic is
extremely self-centered with an
exaggerated sense of
self-importance. for those who may not
know what the word mean. All right,
thank you for that. We hope that
answered your question as we move on
with the time check. Yes, the time is
8:07. Stephen Guggis asks, "What are the
two olive trees in Zechariah
4:E3? What do they represent?"
All right, they represent a very
important role. Brother Jerome, shed
some light on these two olive trees in
Zechariah.
Let's go read
it. When you get it, go ahead and read
it.
Zechariah 4:3.
And two olive trees by it, one upon the
right side of the bowl, and the other
upon the left side thereof.
Okay. Uh these are the two witnesses
that you read about in Revelations the
11th chapter. Okay?
Uh they not Moses, they not Elijah,
they're not any of the uh
patriarchs, you know, uh that's, you
know, cuz the patriarchs, you know, that
they they they dead and they they
waiting on the first resurrection. Okay?
So, it's not any of them. We don't know
what their names are, but we do know
they're going to be Israelites because
the word of God tell us um he told the
children of Israel, "Ye are my
witnesses." Okay. So, let's go to uh
that Revelations 11 chapter and read
about these olive trees cuz they the two
witnesses in the 11th chapter. Okay.
Revelations
11 and pick it up at verse three. Read
it to the
fourth. Go ahead when you get
it. And I will give power unto my two
witnesses and they shall prophesy a
thousand 203 score days clothed in
sackcloth. Mhm. These are the two olive
trees and the two candlesticks standing
before the God of the earth.
Okay.
Now, these two olive trees, they going
to be around during the time of the
great tribulation, and they going to get
killed. And that's why I know for a fact
they can't possibly be Moses or Elijah
or any of the patriarchs that's in the
grave right now waiting on the first
resurrection. These guys going to be
around, but we don't know who they are,
but they going to be witnesses of God.
So more than likely they Israelites, but
we don't know who by name these guys
are. Okay, so now skip down to verse
seven and
8. And when they shall have finished
their testimony, the beast that
ascendeth out of the bottomless pit
shall make war against them, and shall
overcome them and kill them. Mhm. And
their dead body shall lie in the street
of the great city, which spiritually is
called Sodom and Egypt, where also our
Lord was crucified. Yeah. And if you
continue to read through that chapter,
it is sooner or later when that great
tribulation is over, you going to have a
a first resurrection. And them two
witnesses, they gonna come up in that
first
resurrection. That's all I got. Yep. And
they will have power to shut heaven and
and stop the rain days of their prophecy
and have powers to turn the water into
blood. All right, thank you for that,
brother. As we continue to move on to
our next question, moving on. Brit Brett
says, "I normally have my head covered
but sometimes don't when praying. Is it
okay for a woman with long hair to
sometimes pray without covering her
head? And first Corinthians 11 verse1 15
is given. All right, brother Julius. Is
the long hair considered a covering the
substitute when you're praying?
Absolutely
not. This scripture has nothing to do
with having long hair. It has something
to do with the covering of your long
hair.
Let's let's read her scripture and let's
go back and we going to start at verse
one. But Sean, read 11 1 Corinthians 11
and verse 15.
But if a woman have long hair, it is a
glory to her, for her hair is giving her
for a covering. Yes. So is a man's hair.
His hair is given for him for a
covering, too. But let's look at what
this is really talking about.
Let's let's emphasize let's put emphasis
verse one to verse
three. Go ahead, Sean. Be ye followers
of me even as I also am of Christ. Be ye
followers of me even as I also am of
Christ. This is an order. Watch this. Go
ahead. Now I praise you, brethren, that
ye remember me in all things, and keep
the ordinances as I delivered them to
you. Ordinances is something to deal
with with the order of things as I
deliver to you. Now, let me show you
that this has nothing to do with your
natural hair that come out of your
scalp. Read it. But I will have you know
that the head of every man is Christ.
The head of every man is Christ. Because
this is no order. Go ahead. And the head
of the woman is the man. And the head of
the woman is the man. Go ahead. And the
head of Christ is God. So that order is
the father, the son, the man, the woman.
That is the order. Now let's deal with
how to pray when you're praying. Go
ahead.
Every man praying or prophesying having
his head covered dishonor of his head.
Every man praying or
prophesying having his head covered.
That's a head covering, not his natural
scalp. The hair that come out of his
hair. Every man that's praying and
prophesies having his head covered
dishonor his head. And the head of man
is Christ Jesus. Go ahead. Verse five.
But every woman that prayth or
prophesieth with her head uncovered
dishonoreth her head. No. No. You read
that wrong, son. With her hair
uncovered. But every woman that prayth
or prophesieth with her head uncovered
dishonereth her head.
Why? For that is even all one as if she
were shaven. Skip down to verse seven
and read it. For a man indeed ought not
to cover his head. We're talking about a
head covering. When a man is in the
church and praying or prophesying or
when he's at home or when he's at his
car or wherever he's praying or
prophesying, he is to take his baseball
cap or his whatever hair covering that
he got, he's to take it off. Go ahead
and read. For as much as he is the image
and glory of God, but the woman is the
glory of the man. Go ahead. This has
nothing to do with your natural hair.
This is an order of things. Go ahead.
For the man is not of the woman, but the
woman of the man. Go ahead. Neither was
the man created for the woman, but the
woman for the man. Go ahead. For this
cause of the woman to have power on her
head because of the angels. Because of
the angels. I have invited people to the
Israel of God, females. And I said, we
ask you to wear uh bring a head covering
because we are in the church and we are
dealing with prayer. We're dealing with
the word of God, prophecy. And so we
cannot we have to keep the order when
you are in the in the uh church or
reading the scriptures or in prayer. The
head covering applies to the woman. But
nobody no male in the Israel of God has
their head uh has their head covered
because we have to follow the
order. There's an order of things. This
is not talking about the natural hair.
One last
place. Numbers chapter
5. Numbers chapter 5. When a man
suspected his
wife of
infidelity, whether she was to find out
whether she was guilty or not, you can
read the whole thing on your own. Look
what they did with her. Pick it up at
verse 11. Numbers 5 and 11. Sean, read
it.
And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
"Speak unto the children of Israel, and
say unto them, if any man's wife go
aside, and commit a trespass against
him," Skip down to 14. You can read the
whole rest of it on your own. Go ahead.
And the spirit of jealousy come upon him
and he be jealous of his wife and she be
defiled. or if the spirit of jealousy
come upon him and he be jealous of his
wife and she be not defiled. So he don't
know whether she's guilty or whether
she's not guilty. Pick it up in verse
16. What he should do? Go ahead. And the
priest shall bring her near and set her
before the Lord. And set her before the
Lord. And what? Go ahead. And the priest
shall take holy water in an earthland
vessel. And of the dust that is in the
floor of the tabernacle, the priest
shall take and put it into the water. So
he going to make this concussion of
dirty water. Go ahead. And the priest
shall set the woman before the Lord.
Uh-huh. And uncover the woman's head.
And take her hair out. And uncover the
woman's head. That's why the woman has
to have a head covering. Go ahead. And
put the offering of memorial in her
hands, which is the jealousy offering.
So if she was guilty, if she was guilty,
then she would drink the water and her
belly would swell. You could read this
all the way down in verse 20 uh 22. Her
belly would swell if she was not guilty.
But nothing would happen to her, but he
would uncover her head because in
Israel, it was traditional for the women
to have a to have a head covering when
praying or prophesying. You see the
Muslim women do it all the time. They
have their heads covered. They may not
understand the true reasons of it, but
this is where they get it from. So, this
scripture has nothing to do with your
natural hair. It has something to do to
protect you from the evil angels. When I
invite the women uh uh or any woman is
of God, bring a head covering. And the
book tell you to protect you from the
angels. When the women told me, I'm not
coming to your church. Why should I
cover my head? I said, man, is the order
of things. I can read it to you. Guess
what they just did now? The devil just
got to got to them and they missed out
on wisdom, knowledge, and understanding.
So, I'm not wearing my head uh during co
I'm not wearing um no head to no head
coming to your church. I said, "But you
wear a mask for eight hours. I I lay
right there. I'm done."
Let me let me throw in something here.
Mhm.
You know, just like the Lord tell you
that Jesus is is is ah is a covering for
man. Yeah. And man is the head of the
woman. He is a covering. And
Eve ran to Adam when Satan approached
her which is her. We wouldn't be dying
today.
Who is Satan?
an angel. Yes. That's why it said
because of the angels. If Eve had gone
and dealt with Adam, that person over
there is trying to approach me, Adam
would have waved it all off and we
wouldn't be dying today. That is right.
We're dying. We're dying because
Eve was uncovered and that angel, Satan,
the devil, slew the whole creation.
That's all I have to say.
Hey, can can we uh can we read that
verse 10 in that same chapter, brother?
Go ahead. Numbers 5 and verse 10. No. Uh
1 Corinthians 11 and 10
real
quick. When you get it, go ahead and
read that, brother.
First Corinthians 11 and verse 10. Mhm.
It reads, "For this cause of the woman
to have power on her head because of the
angels."
Yep. That's it right there. Yes, sir.
So, you say you were praying, sister,
always keep you a scarf or a hat around
so that you'll always be in proper
order. And that's that's the answer to
that uh to that right there. So it can't
be sometimes.
Can't be sometimes. No, you got to do
it. That's the ordinance of things.
That's the order. Yeah. All right. Well,
hope that that answered your question,
sister, as we move on to our next one.
Continuing on, uh she also asks if both
of your parents abandon you as a child
and as an adult mistreats you when you
try to love them. Is it a sin to cut
them off and love them from a distance?
And Romans 16 verse1 17 is given.
All right, guest caller is quite a bit
in that question and they want to go to
their Romans 16 and 17 and the guest
caller would take it from there. Read
it.
Romans 16 and 17. Now I beseech you,
brethren, mark them which cause division
and offensive contrary to the doctrine
which ye have learned, and avoid them.
Well, if that's what's happening, then
you avoid them. You already said you
treating it with love, but you doing it
from a long distance. If you do that,
look like you are honoring their
wish. The Bible tell you to honor your
mother and your father. So, if they
don't want you to communicate with you
with them, then you're doing what the
Bible tell them to do, told you to do.
You're honoring their wish. That's all I
have to say. All right.
We hope that that answer bring you some
direction as we continue to move on to
our next one. Next question. Ward Boyd
asks, "When we become God, will we also
be able to create a world also?"
Well, when you become God, hey, you have
made it. That is a beautiful thing. And
we are striving every day to get there.
And so, keep a lot of focus on that,
too. But as far as uh will we be able to
create a world also
um let's go and read um in the Old
Testament let's go and read that Isaiah
64 and4 Isaiah 64
and4 because when we when we get into
the God family still going to be some
plans in operation we just don't know
what all they will be Because Isaiah 64
and4 read that brother.
For since the beginning of the world,
men have not heard nor perceived by the
ear, neither hath the eyes seen, oh God,
beside thee, what he hath prepared for
him that waitth for him. Praise the
Lord. Yes indeed. So that's in the Old
Testament. Let's go in the New
Testament. Let's go in that first
Corinthians the second chapter.
1 Corinthians
2. And when you get there, brother, pick
it up at that verse n.
But
as but as it is written, I have not seen
nor ear heard, neither hath entered into
the heart of man the things which God
hath prepared for them that love him.
Yeah. So whether it's in the new or old,
both of those coincide. and what God is
going to allow and have some of that we
have to wait and see because uh you'll
be full of power but we have to first
get there and that's all I got on that.
I just want to become God. I'll be happy
with that. Hey, being a dokeeper brother
is in the God family.
All right, we hope that that answered
your question as we move on to tonight.
Right, Sister Devil? Uh, yes. We are now
into tonight's Q&A for May the TW for
Wednesday, May the 21st,
2025. Harold Peters asks, "Was the
genetic coal of humans, animals,
insects, etc. tampered with as it is
today for instance crossbreeding
etc. Also our size hermaphrodites and
abnormalities web fingers and toes tails
horns bodies completely covered with
hair reminisce of experimentation.
All right. So, we can open this question
up to the panel. But I tell you, sin
brought in all of these abnormalities
for sure. So, open to the panel if
somebody else would like to weigh in.
Yeah, you're asking the wrong people.
You should go and ask the
biologist. That's all I have to say.
All right, we're going to move on to our
next question. Next question. Trice
says, "Can you
explain 1 Corinians 7 verse 15?" I see a
lot of confusion about this scripture.
1 Corinthians 7 and 15. A lot of
confusion. Let's go there, brother Sean.
1 Corinthians 7 and 15. and against
Cara, we'll take it from there.
But if the unbelieving depart, let him
depart. A brother or a sister is not
under bondage in such cases. But God
have called us to peace.
He was confused about
that. You go up and read who are these
brother and sister? These are
non-believers, right? Yep. back
up and say uh if you and see what it
says about if you married to a
nonbeliever. Back up a little higher.
You want to pick it up?
And that verse and the women which have
a husband that believeth not. Verse 13.
Yeah. Verse 13.
and the woman which have a husband that
believeth not. And if he be pleased to
dwell with her, let her not leave him.
For the unbelieving husband is
sanctified by the wife, and the
unbelieving wife is sanctified by the
husband, else your children.
Now, this is a person that don't believe
in in your God. They don't believe in
what you dealing with. But if they
delight in you and they're your spouse,
then don't put them
away. But if they should decide because
of the unbelief in your God that they
are going to leave you, then he said the
sister or brother is not under bondage.
Under bondage of what? Under the bondage
of the h uh marriage
law. They left
you. So if you're not under bondage that
mean you are not bound by the law of
marriage. They left
you. So you are free to go on with your
life. That's all I have to say. Ain't
nothing confusing about
that. You're not under bondage. Bondage
of what?
Marriage. That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question there, Sister Deborah. Next
one. Next question. Netly Kingdom asks,
"Is it wrong for a spouse to withhold
love and affection? What should the
other spouse do if this is happening?"
All right. If a spouse is holding back a
little bit there, guess call them.
Go to 1 Corinthians the 7th chapter.
Read 1-5.
Now concerning the things whereof ye
wrote unto me, it is good for a man not
to touch a woman. Nevertheless, to avoid
fornication, let every man have his own
wife, and let every woman have her own
husband.
Let the husband render unto the wife due
benevolence, and likewise also the wife
unto the husband. The wife have not
power of her own body, but the husband.
And likewise also the husband have not
power of his own body, but the wife.
Defraud ye not one the other, except it
be with consent for a time, that ye may
give yourselves to fasting and prayer,
and come together again, that Satan
tempt you not for your
inconsistency. So now he's telling you
now that if you're in a marriage and you
don't want to uh uh uh deal with your
wife, meet with her or your husband,
then you are being defrauded.
But it don't
say what you should do after that. So I
can't tell you what you should
do. It's all I have to say. All right.
We hope that that answered your question
as we move on to our next one. Yes.
Nate's question being asked is, "I am
new to the Israel of God, but I own and
cater pork and things against the
dietary law. Please advise.
All right. Welcome to the Israel of God.
But brother Julius, can you advise on
owning a catering company
and selling things that against the
dietary law? Well, it's when you come to
the knowledge of the truth such as the
Israel of God, you know, uh sacrifices
and changes must be
made. Let's go to Isaiah the 65th
chapter. Uh Leviticus the 11th chapter.
You can read that on your own, but uh it
tell you. Well, let's go. Let's go to
let's go there. Let's let's do this.
Leviticus the 11th chapter. Sean, let's
move quick if we can. Leviticus 11th
chapter. This is God's dietary
law. This is how I came into the
Israelis of God. Me born and raised in
Arkansas. But when I came into the
knowledge of the truth, I went home and
showed my mother. I said, "Don't cook
this for me no more." Leviticus 11, pick
it up at 1 and 2, and we'll skip. Read
quick, John. And the Lord spake unto
Moses and to Aaron, saying unto them,
"Speak unto the children of Israel,
saying, These are the beasts which ye
shall eat among all the beasts that are
on the earth." Now he gave, you could
read and rest on your own, but then he
gave you stuff that you cannot eat.
Verse four, read it.
Nevertheless, these shall ye not eat of
them that chew the cud, or of them that
divide the hoof, as the camel, because
he chew of the cud, but divideth not the
hoof, he is unclean unto you.
He's unclean. Skip down to verse uh
seven and read it. And the swine, though
he That's the pork. Go ahead. Though he
divide the hoof and be cloven footed,
yet he cheweth not the cud, he is
unclean to you. He is unclean. You can't
eat them. Now, skip down because you say
you cater different things. Skip down to
verse 9 and read it.
These shall ye eat of all um you That's
good. Okay. These shall ye eat of all
that are in the waters. Whatsoever have
fins and scales in the waters, in the
seas, and in the rivers, them shall ye
eat. You whatever got fins and not or
fins and so that's two characteristic
you can eat that verse 12 12 whatsoever
have no fins nor scales in the waters
that shall be an abomination unto you
because God said you can't eat it. It
must have fins and scales. So you can't
eat the catfish. You can't eat the
shrimps. You can't eat the lobsters, the
scallops, and the crab. You can't eat
that. It's got fins nor scales. Now,
let's go to Isaiah the 65th chapter.
Look what the Lord said
here. And I know people have businesses
and everything and catering companies,
but we serve the true living God. And we
serve a God that can bless you under any
condition. Maybe you change a menu and
and God can still bless it. Maybe you'll
teach them how to eat clean. Isaiah
65 verse two. Go ahead, brother.
I have spread out my hands all the day
unto a rebellious people, which walketh
in a way that was not good after their
own thoughts. which walketh in a way
that is not good after their own
thoughts. Go ahead. A people that
provoketh me to anger continually to my
face. Uhhuh. That sacrifice in gardens
and burnth incense upon altars of brick,
which do what? which remain among the
graves and large in the monuments which
eat swine's flesh and broth of
abominable things is in their vessels.
So they eating swine flesh, they cooking
swine flesh and uh shrimp gumbo and all
the unclean stuff that the Lord said
don't eat and make themselves unclean.
Make themselves unclean. And then they
would take you to Acts. Uh, if I'm
permitted to do this, let's go to Acts
chapter 10 because they going to use
this and say just pray over it is
sanctified by God and prayer and don't
call nothing that God is clean, unclean.
Acts chapter 10, Sean. And when you get
it, pick it up at verse 13. Acts 10 and
13. Go ahead and read it. And there came
a voice to him, "Rise, Peter, kill and
eat." But Peter said, "Not so, Lord, for
I have never eaten anything that is
common or unclean." Oh, you mean the
dietary? They the disciples kept the
dietary law. Yes, sir. Even though Peter
didn't understand what the beard should
mean. Go ahead, continue to read. And
the voice spake unto him again the
second time. What God has cleansed that
call not thou come. Now I want you guys
and ladies and gentlemen to underline
common or unclean. God has what God has
cleansed called thou not thou cometh.
But this is a vision to show you. this a
vision. Read verse 17. Go ahead.
Now, while Peter doubted in himself what
this vision which he has seen should
mean because Peter understood God is not
trying to tell me that I should eat
uh uh uh clean. This ain't got nothing
to do with animals. He trying to figure
out what it mean. Go ahead. Behold, the
men which were sent from Cornelius had
made inquiry for Simon's house and stood
before the gate. Now he said at verse
15, where God has cleansed that called
not thou coming, the Lord has used the
Peter to bring the first Gentile into
the New Testament church. Now Peter
understood what the vision mean two
words, common or unclean. Read verse 28
and get the answer and that'll be it. Go
ahead and read it. And he said unto
them, "Ye know how that it is an
unlawful thing for a man that is a Jew
to keep company or come unto one of
another nation." Uh-huh. But God has
showed me that I should not call any man
common or unclean. Oh, that's what the
vision God is trying to tell me.
Cornelius, a devout man that feared God
and gave much arms to the people and had
respect among the Jews, was good to him.
He prayed an angel out of heaven and the
angel sent him to Peter and Peter did
not. And then the same angel went down
and told Peter, you got to go teach
this. You got to go teach
Cornelius. So he found out, hey, God has
shown me not to call any man common or
unclean. Skip all the way down to verse
35 and go ahead. 34. Go ahead. Then
Peter opened his mouth and said, "Of a
truth I perceive that God is no
respector of persons." No, God is no
respector of animals. That God is no
respector of persons. Continue to read.
But in every nation, he that fearth him
and workketh righteousness is accepted
with him. And that's why Cornelius was
accepted of him because he worketh
righteous. He was a devout man. This
whole scripture has nothing to do with
animals. It has something to do with the
Gentiles who are called wild beasts, but
we're talking men. But it's using
animals to describe nations. Like we
have Chicago Bears, a team of men,
Chicago Cubs, Detroit Tigers, wild
beasts that describing men. So that's
all this means. I hope that helped. So
Julius, could you again, he's stating
that
uh he owns and cater pork and things
against the dietary law. Please adise.
The advice
is, hey, you pray to God, ask him
because evidently you you fear the Lord
and you trying, it's it's a concern to
you. You could change your menu. You
could change your menu and God can still
bless you. Instead of the unclean stuff,
replace it with the clean stuff. And
then thereby you can still teach the
people how to eat clean. They will
inquire, why you don't sell this no
more? Well, you know what? I got rid of
that menu. This is what I sell now. The
Lord can bless you in any situation. He
can bless that menu and bless your
business. But it's it's according to
your faith.
Well, you know, I will
say that the Lord say you cannot serve
God and mammon too. Yes. Yes, sir.
And so,
uh, somebody read that and I think we
leave it alone.
No man can serve two
masters. Where that
Sean? You cannot serve Luke Luke 16.
Let's go to Luke 16. And I believe it's
that verse 13 that we're looking for.
Luke
16, let me see. And uh 13. Yeah, that's
it.
And with all due respect at the Israel
of God, we do our best to to stick to
the
strips and try to be obedient service as
much as possible.
Verse 13,
you're not concerned about the God and
what we do. You better be concerned
about what God do.
So read that.
Luke 16 and 13. It reads, "Yep. No
servant can serve two masters, for
either he will hate the one and love the
other, or else he will hold to the one
and despise the other. Ye cannot serve
God and mammon.
So, whoever this uh uh person is, all I
have to say to you is you have a
decision to
make. That's all I have to say.
All right, we're going to leave it
there. We're going to move on to our
next question with a time check. Yes,
the time is
8:41. Vita Love asks for the scripture
regarding a woman's cycle and when are
they clean after it?
All right. Regarding a woman's
monthly and when is she clean after it?
Let's open that up to the
panel and u take it from there.
Let's go and read it wherever it is. All
right, let's go into that search mode so
we can find
that.
Um let's
see. Leviticus
15. Yeah, 19.
Yes. Leviticus 15 and 19 starting at 19.
Yes, sir.
It reads, "And if a woman have an issue,
and her issue in her flesh be blood, she
shall be put apart seven days, and
whosoever toucheth her shall be unclean
until the evening."
Amen.
and everything that she lith upon in her
separation shall be unclean. Everything
also that she siteth upon shall be
unclean. And whosoever toucheth her and
whosoever toucheth her bed shall wash
his clothes and bathe himself in water
and be unclean until the evening.
And whosoever toucheth anything that she
sat upon shall wash his clothes, and
bathe himself in water, and be unclean
until the
evening. And if it be on her bed, or on
anything whereon she siteth, when he
toucheth it, he shall be unclean until
the evening.
And if any man lie with her at all, and
her flowers be upon him, he shall be
unclean seven days. And all the bed
whereon he lith shall be
unclean. And if a woman had
Why don't you get down to the point
where we tell you when she was be
unclean? Well, she will be clean.
Skip down to 28. 28. Yep.
28 reads, "But if she be cleansed of her
issue, then she shall number to herself
seven days, and after that she shall be
clean, and on the eighth day she shall
take unto her two turtles or two young
pigeons, and bring them unto the priest
to the door of the tabernacle of the
congregation."
Well, the old thing, we don't do the
pigeon or nothing like that since Jesus
died. for the woman when she come down
on her cycle. I don't whether she uh uh
uh uh bleed for the whole seven days or
not. On the eighth day, if she if she
stopped on the seventh day, then the
next day she is she is clean. If she
only uh uh the cycle only lasts for
three days, still she have to go the
full seven days and on the eight days
she Okay.
Yeah.
want to go two weeks. No, you go one
week. That's why it's called a week of
separation. When you come on your
period, go you cancel you seven days. If
your period is stopped in the eighth
day, you're clean.
Yeah. And it and if her if her um period
goes beyond her usual seven days, she
can't start her count until she stops
bleeding at that point. Correct.
That is correct. Yeah. And that's that
verse 25. Sean, read that.
And if a woman have an issue of her
blood many days out of the time of her
separation, or if it run beyond the time
of her separation, all the days of the
issue of her uncleanness shall be as the
days of her separation, she shall be
unclean.
All right. So, we hope that that answers
your question as we continue to move on.
Moving on. Most most love asks, "Do the
ones that make it into the first
resurrection, will they be in the
wilderness also?"
The ones that make it to the first
resurrection. What was that question?
And go ahead, repeat question again.
Yes.
Do the ones that make it into the first
resurrection, will they be in the
wilderness
also? Well, I know two won't be in the w
I know some won't be in the wilderness.
The rubel and the people that's going to
be building the temple while Jesus is in
the wilderness with the people. Now,
whether they be in the wilderness or all
of them be in the wilderness, the book
don't say. So, we can't answer that
question. All I know is all the flesh
and blood people out of Israel have to
go through the wilderness and Jesus will
deal with them
now for three and a half years.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next question. 45 under asks, "What
should I tell a person that messed up in
the truth?"
What should you tell a person that
messed up in the truth?
Yes.
Hey, dustireselves off and keep running
this race for eternal life.
Ezekiel
18, son. early. Do not let sin be your
ruin. Right? Don't die in your sins. We
we mentioned a righteous man fall seven
times and get back up. And but let's go
read that. Let's go to Proverbs 24 and
read verse
16. Proverbs 24 and 16.
Proverbs 24-16. It reads, "For a just
man fallth seven times and riseth up
again, but the wicked shall fall into
mischief and they stay there." So the
wicked will stay in mischief. But if you
fall and you a just man, you going to
get back up. You going to repent and you
going to fight this good fight all the
way through.
But like we were saying earlier that
look if you know better you should be
doing better. That should be your every
thought to do what God is calling you to
do. You know as long let's let's go to
uh
Ecclesiastics 9 right quick and read
verse four.
Ecclesiastes 9 and verse4. Go ahead.
For to him that is joined to all the
living there is hope. For a living dog
is better than a dead lion. Go ahead.
For the living know that they shall die,
but the dead know not anything. Neither
have they anymore a reward. For the
memory of them is forgotten. Go ahead.
Also their love and their hatred and
their envy is now perished. Neither have
they any more a portion forever in
anything that is done under the sun. So
there is hope for the living. But if you
die in your sins, there is no hope. The
thing is that is why you should be we
should be conscious of what we do at all
times. Uh that's that's all I got. But
but you can use David as an example.
Yes, sir. He uh made adultery with a
man's wife and had a man killed. But he
going to be king of
Israel during the millennium period.
Why? Is because his transgression and he
repented. Yes, sir. That's what Ezekiel
walked straight from that that day on.
Mhm. And that that Psalm 51 is is David
speaking to that strongly. Read that on
your own.
Yeah. Ezekiel Ezekiel 18 and 30 says,
"Repent and turn yourself from all your
transgressions so iniquity will not be
your ruin." Your ruin.
Yeah. thief on the
cross. I mean, there's a there's a few
examples we can use that, hey, just keep
fighting. Long as you got a day, just
keep fighting and do what's right. And
hey, we'll see what happens. All right,
we hope that that answered your question
as we move on to our next one. Uh, yes.
Uh, I want to say to Mark Ash that his
question was answered. It was the second
one at the beginning of the program. So
Mark Ash, your question was already
answered. Now moving on. Zion asked for
an explanation for Genesis 3 verse 15.
They would like an explanation on
Genesis the 3
chapter and picking it up at that verse
15. Genesis 3 and 15 about the enmity
between the woman and her seed. Go
ahead, Sean.
And I will put enmity between thee and
the woman, and between thy seed and her
seed. It shall bruise thy head and thou
shalt bruise his heel.
Open to the panel.
Well, the woman's seed is talking about
Jesus. Go to the 12th chapter of
Revelation. Read uh one and two and skip
down to verse five.
It reads, "And there appeared a great
wonder in heaven, a woman clothed with
the sun and the moon under her feet, and
upon her head a crown of 12 stars. And
she being with
child and she being with child cried,
travailing in birth, and pain to be
delivered." Y Okay. Now, now this woman
is talking about Israel. on your own.
You can go and read Genesis the 37th
chapter that let you talking about this
uh uh this woman is talking about Israel
and the
seed is uh is talking about Jesus. Skip
down to verse five. So she was traveled
to be delivered and what did she bring
forth? Verse five. And she brought forth
a manchild who was to rule all nations
with the rod of iron. And her child was
caught up unto God and to his throne.
Yeah. Okay. There's always going to be
enmity between Satan and Jesus. Now, now
Satan drew Jesus heal because but by
because he because he had to come and
die to to save the
creation. But then Jesus going to bruise
his head. He going to throw him in the
lake of fire. He ain't going to come out
no more.
That's all I have to say.
All right, that answered your question
as we move on to our next one. Okay,
moving on to the next one. Uh, King Joo
Judas says, "If you have a
friend, one moment. If you have a friend
or a family member graduating from a
Christian Bible college, is it a sin or
an error if I attend the ceremony or
support the person at all?
Sounds like a personal choice.
Sound like a personal choice. And u
let's go read that saying I heard you
talk about there, Julius.
First John 3 and4.
Read it. Whosoever committh sin,
transgresseth also the law. For sin is
the transgression of the law.
So that's what see
ask the question again.
Yes. The question was if you have a
friend or a family member graduating
from a Christian Bible
uh
college. Is it a sin or in an error if I
attend the ceremony or support the
person at all?
It depends on what he's teaching. But
it's not a sin.
Sin is transgression of the law. That's
your choice to go. But then as far as
support is concerned, it all depends on
what he learned at that Bible college.
Mhm.
If he said if they if they teaching him
that people are going to go to heaven,
you can't support that. No. Satan in the
ground people in hell. You can't support
that.
The Lord's day. You can't support that.
You can eat anything. All you got to do
is pray over it. You can't support that.
That's all I have to say. Yeah. Cuz uh
like the book say, can two walk together
except they be agreed?
So, right. Can we read Can we read 1
Corinthians the 9th chapter
and verse 22?
1 Corinthians 9 and 22.
Like like
uh you know like we said sin is the
transgression of the law. But I mean
that could be a chance to uh you know
bring somebody into the truth. And uh
this 1 Corinthians 9:22 it reads to the
weak became I as weak that I might gain
the weak. I am made all things to all
men that I might by all means save some.
And this I do for the gospel's sake that
I might be partaker thereof with you.
Yeah. All right. Yeah. So, his other
question is, "Is it wrong or sin?" And
we know it's not a sin, but is it wrong
or or he says or a sin for an Israelite
to attend a Bible Christian college to
further their knowledge of scriptures
and earn a degree in the process?
I'm going answer
that. I don't care what Bible college
you go to. These Bible colleges were set
up by Gentiles.
Yeah. The Lord and and I'm I'm going to
let you know who the Lord gave his word.
Go to Romans the 9th chapter and start
reading at verse one.
Romans 9 and verse one. It reads, "I say
the truth in Christ, I lie not. My
conscience also bearing me witness in
the Holy Ghost that I have great
heaviness and continual sorrow in my
heart.
For I could wish that myself were a
curse from Christ for my brethren, my
kinsmen according to the flesh, who are
Israelites, to whom pertain of the
adoption and the glory and the covenants
and the giving of the law and the
service of God and the
promises whose are the
Okay. Everything he gave Israel, didn't
he? Yeah. Yeah, up to Romans the third
chapter and read verse one.
Romans 3.
In the meantime, somebody go in the
Psalms and show us what show where the
Lord say he gave his word to Israel and
nobody else. But you read Romans 3
and Romans 3 and1 it reads, "What
advantage then have the Jew? Or what
profit is there of circumcision?
much every way chiefly because that unto
them were committed the oracles of God.
Now the oracles of God is committed to
us. Okay. Yeah. Somebody go in and and
read where Jesus who the Lord uh uh gave
his word to. Psalm 147 19 and 20.
Read it.
Psalms 147 19 and 20. It reads, "He
showeth his word unto Jacob, his
statutes, and his judgments unto Israel.
He have not dealt so with any nation,
and as for his judgments, they have not
known them. Praise ye the Lord." Now
look, he showed he showed the word to
Israel. All of the apostles are
Israelites. All the apostles was
Israelites. Jesus came in the flesh as
an Israelite. Now, let's show you what
did Jesus say about salvation. Go to St.
John the third chapter where he's
talking to
Nicodemus and see what he told this
woman. Uh, fourth chapter, I'm sorry,
fourth chapter where he's talking to
this woman at the well when she said
that her father's worship in that
mountain. Start there. Verse 20. Verse
20. St. John 4 and verse 20. It reads,
"Our fathers worship in this mountain,
and ye say that in Jerusalem is the
place where men ought to
worship." Jesus saith unto her, Woman,
believe me, the hour cometh, when ye
shall neither in this mountain, nor yet
at Jerusalem worship the
Father. Ye worship ye know not what. We
know what we worship, for salvation is
of the Jews.
That's point blank. So, how you going to
go to one of these Gentile, you being an
Israelite gentile school, and further
your information?
Somebody need to study some more. That's
all I have to say.
You only have I known of all the
families of the
earth. All right,
Sister Deborah.
Yes. Uh this question you can answer
quickly. Can you celebrate birthdays?
Ain't nothing in the Bible
against nothing.
Nothing in the Bible against celebrating
your birthday and thanking God for
another year, another 12 months and you
still in the game. So ain't nothing
against you celebrating your birthday.
And we can't go to what the scriptures
say that somebody was doing evil on
their birthdays, which was Pharaoh. And
who was that? I think it was
Nebuchad. That's correct.
Listen, go to Revelation 20th chapter
and see what you going to be judged out
of.
Revelation 20. Yep.
And the book is open.
Yeah.
And
uh verse 12, Revelation 20 and verse 12,
it reads, "And I saw the dead, small and
great, stand before God, and the books
were open, and another book was open,
which is the book of life. And the dead
were judged out of those things which
were written in the books, according to
their works."
So you judge out of this Bible. Those
are the books. That's why it's called
the Bible. the Greek word for Bible's
biblo, which is a binding of books. Now,
you going to be judged out of what's
written in this book. Now, when you can
go in there and say, "Thou shalt not
celebrate birthdays," then you can say
it. But if you say you can't, then you
need to remember what the Lord said was
written in the last uh verse of
Revelation 22. Go read that. That's
Revelation 22,
right? About adding and taking from it.
18 and 19. Revelation 22:18 and 19. It
reads, "For I testify unto every man
that heareth the words of the prophecy
of this book. If any man shall add unto
these things, God shall add unto him the
plagues that are written in this book.
And if any man shall take away from the
words of this book of this prophecy, God
shall take away his part out of the book
of life and out of the holy city and
from the things which are written in
this book. You notice how he emphasized
in this book. Yeah. Believe what you
want. But I want you to beware if you
going to start deciding
what is saying and what is not. What you
can do and what you cannot do. And you
can't read it out of this book. That's
all I have to say. Yep. That's correct.
And for the Old Testament Christians in
that Deuteronomy 4 and two, you shall
not add unto the word which I command
you, neither shall ye diminish all from
it, that you may keep the commandments
of the Lord your God, which I command
you.
All right, Sister Deborah.
Yes. And that question was asked by
Black Mode and the time is 9:04.
All right, 9:04. All right, we have ran
out of time. And we want to thank
everybody who tuned in with us from all
around the world. And if you submitted a
question, we didn't have a chance to get
to it. We will deal with that question
next week. Please don't resubmit it.
Sister Deborah, take it. Put it in
rotation. But we'd like to thank you
again. And we'd like to say until we all
come together again, be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all. As brother
Shan closes us out.
Our Father, which are in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread, and forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debtors, and lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we pray.